So important terms when we manage
communications, not rocket science,
but also important.
So we have dimensions of communication,
internal within the organization,
external, outside of the organization.
Formal and informal, verbal and written,
official, like annual
reports and unofficial.
Nonverbal, don't forget the body language,
hand gestures, facial expressions,
I've made a lot already.
I make even more in my class.
Sphere of influence that we want to
consider when communicating.
Upward, when we're communicating to senior
management, downward to team members,
sidewards, peers within the organization,
or outward, outside of the organization.
We also have the five Cs of written
communications.
We should use correct grammar and special.
telling.
Eliminate excess words.
You don't have to try to sound smart.
And use a concise expression.
Express a clear purpose directed to the
needs of the reader.
Not just what you want to communicate out,
what they've asked for.
Ideas should be coherent and there should
be a logical flow.
And we should control the flow of words
and ideas.
So the last project, a large project I was
on was out in Dallas, Texas, and it was in
the marketing communications department
for a health care organization.
And so that was like 2010-ish,
I believe.
They made it, it became industry standard,
so EF, that no marketing communications
would go out over the seventh grade level
to make sure everybody understood it.
So there's an example for you.
Moving on, we'll cover some more.
Thank you.